Panama Mexico all the other ones so I
grew up outside Seattle in a little town
called Tucson Arizona and when people
here I'm from a border state they say Oh
immigrations bright a big problem and I
say no it's not because I happen to know
a lot of stuff all right I didn't
graduate from the University of Arizona
with a degree in International Studies
at all but
[Music]
I listen and I read a lot of stories on
YouTube and I know immigrations not a
problem it's a combination of problems
with a capital that's too much for most
people wrap their brains around well
lucky for you my brain is flexible other
than that you say think outside the box
I say how high
immigration is actually two problems one
we got a bunch of people who want to be
in our country because we're number one
and B stands for border we have a border
that's too long to protect have you
looked at a map recently it's a 2,000
mile dotted line well no wonder so many
people are getting through it's a dotted
line that's 2,000 miles long hola do you
know how long the Panama Canal is
probably not it's only ten miles see I
told you I happen to know a lot of stuff
now the other day after bath time my mom
Pat came down to the basement
but she knocked first which is our new
rule and we were watching the news from
Washington and she said I should share
my great ideas with the White House
because I'm a problem thinker and I've
got the doctor's note to prove it but I
didn't I didn't come here tonight to
talk about Pat because she's not the
boss of me right now
I came here to tell you that when we
issue my shorter border order
immigration won't be a problem anymore
it's simple we move the border to the
Panama Canal which is short and very
secure what with all those locks and
then we take over all the countries
between here and there
Panama Mexico all the other ones so all
the people who want to come here to
America won't have to come here because
they'll already be here except down
there where they are already but now
they'll be paying taxes to Uncle Sam
instead of uncle tio or whoever I don't
know which one of their relatives is in
charge of that but we'll make a bunch of
money in taxes and the border will be
shorter and easier to keep an order
you're totally welcome
I just killed two birds with one stone
because that's how I roll I'm Robert
Mack and I kill birds and I'm traveling
the country sharing my plans and I've
realized we have a lot of red people in
our country and a lot of blue people and
I think we need more purple people like
Prince and honor of princes memory I
think America's forecast is for some
Purple Rain because right now our
country is by polarized it's black and
white and gay and straight and young and
old and male and female and we need
something more like Prince
whatever whatever that was
more back because the two-party system
doesn't work or maybe it's me maybe I'm
just like my mom Pat she's never
satisfied with anything that I do why do
we scream at each other do you even know
what it sounds like when doves cry I do
because I killed Birds hi I'm Robert Mac
from robber matcom thanks
and thanks for coming tonight I know you
didn't have to you could have stayed in
and turn your brain off and stuck your
head in front of that rectangle with the
endless parade of changing characters it
turns your brain into mush right stupid
books
can bucks talk to you and show you
moving pictures I don't think so
save a tree watch TV that's my message
to you tonight
[Applause]
I have a lot of good ideas like that my
brain is so dense with ideas I don't
want to make it sound like I'm bragging
but I'm probably the densest person in
this room in fact one of America's
smartest doctors is so interested in my
great ideas that she interviews me every
week in her office for nearly an hour
[Laughter]
during our last interview session she
calls them sessions because they're
obviously like music to her ears
I called him obsessions because she
writes down everything that I say she
asked me Robert Mack from rubber matcom
if your house ront fire and you can only
remove one thing what would it be and as
always there are no right or wrong
answers and I said well I probably
remove the fire
[Applause]
which i believe is the right answer
last week I wore t-shirt and shorts and
then also heavy winter coat and then I
had to get out a bunch of rain gear then
on Tuesday seriously I cannot believe
this weather because I'm an atheist and
we have trouble believing but
it's not as bad as my neighbor he's
agnostic he doesn't know whether or not
we have whether or not I heard I heard
some disturbing weather news recently a
bunch of a bunch of science men said a
couple of things the science men and the
science ladies that they reluctantly
allowed on board I don't you call times
for a second times for many years it was
just science men and then they said fine
fine we'll allow a science lady and the
first science lady was Marie Curie who's
the only person to win two different
Nobel prizes in two different fields of
science and she discovered radiation and
she discovered the only substance harder
than diamonds it's an avocado from
Trader Joe's
what if the Russians were able to
weaponize that technology if that
and that avocado fell into the wrong
hands
it would crush those hands
times back in anyway the the science
Minh they said a couple of things they
said every year they look at all the
numbers and generally for the most part
July of any given month is the hottest
month of that year and I thought back
when I was a kid
fourth of July always hot always July
the evidence bears that out I'm not I'm
not gonna argue with that all right but
what they said next was a little they
said July of last year was the hottest
month on earth ever and that's a bold
thing to say because we're not done with
ever yet okay it's a little early to be
handing out trophies okay it might not
even be the hottest month of the decade
let's just see how it plays out okay
science man ever for the earth began
when the earth began which is 4.5
billion years ago and two and a half
years I've done all the research so you
guys don't have to and I talked to the
specialist and they told me that the
earth is 4.5 billion years old and that
was about two and a half years ago so
you would have to add that to its age
and and then the earth will continue to
exist for another five to seven billion
years - the two and a half years that
have already transpired at which time
the Sun will turn into a red giant and
consume the earth so that that period of
time that's that stretch of time is ever
for the earth and we're not even halfway
done and you don't crown a champion
before midseason
all right I'm I'm no gambling guy but if
I were I'd put all my money on probably
the last month of ever I bet you pretty
warm I think
[Applause]
when the Sun expands 250 times its size
and turns into a 5,000 degree ball of
nuclear fusion vaporizing every atomic
bomb that holds the Earth's very
existence together that's got to be
hotter than July when it gets hot do
what I do take a summer vacation to
Alaska yeah 7 days 1 night
that wasn't everybody so please explain
that to the quiet people
I don't like July my favorite month is
January because that's when my birthday
is
that's the best month we have it's the
best month to have a birthday because
you don't have to wait as long and it's
also
it's the time of year that you get a
fresh start I joined a health club
because this year because I decided I
want to lose about thirty dollars a
month
and also I like I like January because I
do a lot of I do a lot of Christmas
parties for companies and those are in
December but now a lot of companies are
doing their parties in January and I did
one that was great they flew me out to
California and put me up at a nice place
facing the ocean the Atlantic and
I was watching The History Channel and
sure it's nothing but repeats
but I learned something fascinating
about California it's the most diverse
state in the country because 160 years
ago there weren't a lot of people living
there and then one guy found one little
piece of gold and then men from every
corner of the planet came to strike it
rich and then they were followed by
women who follow men who follow money
and that's pretty much how the West was
won first the gold diggers and then the
gold diggers
and it may it makes California very
diverse which is fine but also very
politically correct because they don't
want anyone to be offended by anything
so they they didn't call it a Christmas
party I said it's a Christmas party and
they said well no don't don't say that
and I said well then I'll say Happy
Hanukkah too and they're like no because
then you'll have to say I have a
beautiful Boxing Day in a quasi Kwanzaa
and a terrific Tim can just forget it
it's a holiday party just call it a
holiday party and they changed the songs
they didn't play I'm dreaming of a white
Christmas for two reasons
on that one and
Frosty the Snowman is now Kaitlynn a
person of snow
[Laughter]
we three kings of Orient are very
offended that you would say Orient you
can't say Orient any more because they
don't want to offend Asians and you
can't say spick-and-span any more
because they don't want to offend
Latinos yeah you you have to say
spic-and-span iord it's very very touchy
you can't even order a Black Russian in
a bar encounter plan excuse me I'd like
a former Soviet republic of African
descent on the rocks I travel a lot
because I'm better than you
and
I was in Oklahoma recently have you been
to Oklahoma ma'am no save your bus fare
okay because it's nothing like the
musical in Oklahoma I did not have fun
there there was a lot of booing going on
during my presentation and I'm sorry but
a crowd has to be really really stupid
for me to boo them
[Laughter]
I'm driving through the flat part of the
state and
to get to a better State anyway I'm
driving and I'll admit I'm not the best
driver I'm probably the only person who
ever lost control driving through Mirage
I didn't even see it anyway I'm driving
and I hit a rabbit and I felt horrible
about it I had to look it turns out it
wasn't a rabbit it was a cabriolet it's
a Volkswagen Rabbit with a different top
maybe I didn't mean for that to be funny
maybe that's not a joke at all maybe
that's a setup for another joke later on
and when we get there it'll be hilarious
and make up for this awkwardness that
you've created here I got hired to work
in in North Carolina which is a
beautiful place if you don't live in
North Carolina it's kind of inconvenient
though because they keep it pretty far
away from where I live and it was a
lunchtime event so I had to I had to
wake up extra early and then I had a
long drive to go to get there on time
it's a you know six seven hour drive and
so I got up early had extra coffee which
is a great idea unless you happen to
have a bladder which
which I do and it's tremendous I'm
driving down there and my clock is
telling me just go
don't just keep going but my biner is
telling me to stop stop so uh there was
a rest stop and I pulled over and I
stopped but I didn't rest right I ran to
the men's room closed for repairs okay
but the women's room was open
now I didn't bring my birth certificate
with me on this particular trip to North
Carolina
but there's known around and so I went
into the the ladies room now there the
government is in charge of the the
freeways and the rest stops and I was
standing there facing the toilet and I
realized oh there may be some federales
gonna come by and look under the stall
and see that my feet are pointed toward
the toilet right so I turn around
and I sat down and did it like a lady
and I'll tell you it was a revelation I
had two free hands and my phone I
replied to some emails
check the scores and my stocks sent out
a couple tweets I've never been so
productive in my life and that's how the
North Carolina House bill to change my
life forever because now I'm a VP ladies
style and I get stuff done that was in
Bryce Canyon in southern Utah if you
haven't been there it's it's these red
sandstone arches and towers it's where
they filmed the Roadrunner cartoons back
when they film cartoons on location
before all the animal rights protesters
came in and shut down the Acme rockets
gate company once and for all and it's
beautiful but it's Utah so they say it's
beautiful well it's not be Utah full
when you're camping in a slot canyon and
there's a cloudburst flash flood they
kicked us all out I had to get a hotel
nothing fancy just a room in this little
mom-and-pop and mom and mom and mom and
mom and mom place
[Applause]
why do you think they're called more
moms
speaking of moms the other day after
morning nap
my mom Pat came down to the basement
even though she's not allowed to without
permission and she said stop eating all
the chicken salad I said I could have as
much chicken salad as I want if he
didn't want me to have any chicken salad
you shouldn't have put it on the share
shelf in the first place and she got
really matches no don't eat the chicken
salad because I might be tainted with
that avian bird flu that's come back and
he's already killed a couple people in
Canada and a couple months before that
was the the e.coli that was in the
Chipotle burrito place and a few years
before that was the Salmonella that was
in the spinach and a bunch of people got
sick from that and then before that was
the Listeria in the cantaloupe and like
30 people died from that and a few years
before that was a mad cow disease that
came a couple different times and then
before that was that tainted apple juice
that killed some people and a couple
years before that was that tainted OJ
that killed two people with a knife
[Applause]
true story it's a true story my mom Pat
travels and it's great because every
time she leaves I don't have a curfew
for like two weeks and I could play my
own late-night make-believe talk show
it's called don't go to bed with Robert
Mack anyway that's not funny I don't
know why you're laughing at that she
left and went on a trip to the South
Pacific have you been in the South
Pacific
no it's nothing like the musical yeah
you let the next one don't worry about
it anyway she sent me a postcard with a
picture of the platypus
does anyone know anything about the
platypus it's not a well-understood
creature anyone it's it's it's what
males are poisonous yeah that's true
it's uh it's a messed up animal I don't
know how it it's so different but it's
it has poisonous Spurs in its feet and
it's it's a leg I studied in high school
so I know a little bit about it have you
been in high school it's nothing like
the musical
[Applause]
it has warm-blooded fur like a mammal
but on the other hand it lays eggs it's
got the cool thing about its it shoots
poison out of its feet and they don't
know why it's electric like an electric
eel but and they don't know why about
that and then it shoots poison like if
you're chasing it it'll shoot poison can
you shoot poison out of your feet I was
thinking if anyone on the planet could
do that maybe James Bond on a good day
at least that's kind of believable you
know well Mr Bond this is it not yet
[Music]
Sean Connery is platypus it's a long way
to go to say platypus see I know but I'm
not gonna leave you hanging there
because the platypus it's a much funnier
animal than that it's like us it has a
warm blood and fur like a mammal but on
the other hand it lays eggs and has a
duckbill like a bird it's the el camino
of the animal kingdom el camino is half
car half truck it's the Jackalope of the
auto industry a Jackalope is a rabbit
with a different top it's a Cabriolet
[Applause]
I'm excited to be here I didn't I didn't
know if I was gonna there make it here
because there was an accident on the big
road where I live on the way to the
airport and if I missed my flight then I
wouldn't be here and I don't think
anybody got hurt but I'm I'm lucky to be
here tonight all right almost as lucky
as you are but not everybody knows how
to drive on the big road so I thought I
would maybe tell you so why don't you
sit down and listen up all right the big
road is a tapestry of lanes there's a
passing lane and when you want to pass
someone you get in the passing lane and
you pass them it's pretty simple when
you think about it but not everybody
does because if you're in the passing
lane and cars in the slow lane are going
faster than you you my friend are a hole
in the tapestry okay you're a pass hole
and maybe you should spend your time on
the little roads okay I told you I'm not
the best driver and I remember this one
time
Robert Frost once told me a story about
taking a fork in the road yes he did he
said two roads diverged in the wood and
I took the one less traveled by bla bla
bla and paraphrasing but when you're on
the big road sometimes people see you
laying next to them open up and they
think it's a fork in the road they got
to take the fork in the road so they'll
be in this lane for a minute and this
lane opens up and they get into that
lane for three seconds and they realize
there's an opening back here in the lane
where they were and so they get back in
that lane hey just because it's a
tapestry doesn't mean you have to weave
the whole time alright
stupid Forker I told you I'm not that
strong of a driver Robert Plant of the
Led Zeppelin's once told me a story
about taking a fork in the road yes he
did he said yes there are two paths you
can go by but in the long run there's
still time to change the road you're on
and it makes me wonder yeah it makes me
wonder how you got your driver's license
in the first place because between you
pass holes were crawling in the wrong
lane and youth workers who are darting
back and forth leaving behind a trail of
swears and middle fingers it takes me
forever to get to my job of being a
professional communicator of which being
good at I am one of them guys
[Applause]
I am I'm a motivational speaker and I'm
really good I speak to people and five
minutes later they're on their feet
motivated out of the building to do
something better with their lives
sometimes you're even running I have the
key that unlocks doors in people's minds
why do you think they call me door key
okay hi because my mom keeps my Star
Wars action figures locked up in another
room no that's just a coincidence it's
because opened doors and people's minds
and I bussed tables at Applebee's I
motivate people to do good things and I
wean them off their bad habits I'm a
huge wiener you can go online Google it
up and tell me what you see
probably boy
but you don't have to believe me I do my
lectures and seminars all over North
America and people go out of their way
to send feedback about what a great
experience they had being around me this
one guy compared his life to a to a
broken down house and he said I was this
big hammer that helped him refix up his
house
what he said was um this guy's a big
tool you're welcome
they go out of their way to send me this
feedback here's another one you've
proven to me that anyone could do
anything no matter what little talent
they have run with that
I want those two hours back I can't get
enough of me
this one's great my lawyers will be
contacting you
I smell a movie deal I'm not a doctor I
don't pretend to be a doctor but I've
helped people with their ailments
somebody wrote in and said you've cured
my insomnia
I don't know what it is either
this one's great it was like listening
to a fax machine because that's what I
am I'm a machine full of facts and
that's how I'm able to motivate people
is one fact at a time and here's a
freebie you guys might want to jot this
down it's a great way to start your day
at home are you bringing in the office
and put it on a sticky on your computer
you've probably heard part of this
before it takes 26 muscles to frown at
somebody but only six it only takes six
muscles to text them a colon with a
frowny face
[Applause]
I don't see anybody writing that down
here's another interesting fact I read
online the other day 1/5 of the world is
Chinese I was speechless too because
that's almost 20 percent so look we are
sitting alright if the two people next
you aren't Chinese and the people in
front and behind you aren't Chinese
guess what yeah Ming
you're mathematically Chinese
Nihao
zài jiàn I'm not Chinese
and I'm kind of a opposed right now and
it's not just because of what they're
doing to the people in Tibbett all right
it's the whole it's the whole Chinese
New Year scam which I discovered this
year there's the global warming hoax
that they invented yeah yeah they say Oh
what happens when it gets really hot or
really cold you get an air-conditioner
or you get a space heater which are
built in China all right so it totally
makes sense
same thing with the gluten thing gluten
wasn't a thing 15 years ago now
according to China oh if you eat too
much wheat you're gonna get sick
according to the world's largest
producer of rice come on people
follow the money
somebody said I should check out the
Chinese New Year this year and so it was
around Valentine's Day was year the
rooster I went to San Francisco
California because they have the largest
Chinatown in the world that's a fact
there are larger ones in China boy but
over there they're just called towns
anyway it was a you're the rooster but I
partied like it was Dragon oh yeah
Moo goo gai pan out the yin-yang I tell
you all you can eat and dim sum
and they clear the plates and I'll all I
have is this government issue Chinese
zodiac placemat that says Happy New Year
in the middle of February and to me
that's a red flag I don't think the
first day of the new year should be
hiding in the middle of the second month
right something fishy going on I did a
little research turns out Chinese New
Year starts on a different day every
year maybe it's the middle of February
maybe it's June 52nd but it always
manages to end up on the day of a parade
yeah interesting that's another red flag
a big one with yellow stars if you know
what I mean there's something going on I
have a lot of products that are built in
China with a year-long warranty and I'm
afraid
if they're gonna rip me off somehow hey
I've got this air conditioner that I got
for global warming and it's supposed to
expire in 2018 and they're home no
that's gonna expire in rat there's
something going on I don't know what it
is I looked up my birthday I was born in
near the monkey that's what my place man
has always told me and why would a
placemat lie to me it doesn't make any
sense but turns out the year I was born
near the monkey didn't start till
February I was born in January so
technically it was still goat outside
when I was born and I'm a little upset
about that I don't know if anyone here
has ever been demoted to goat before
I've been living a lie all of these
years I thought it was skillful and
flexible and creative no it turns out
I'm compassionate and fancy and I like
rabbits well I don't like rabbits and I
don't like people telling me to like
rabbits okay so fancy I'll take the
upgrade on that but I'm I'm done with
you China that's it I said I'm
boycotting you right so sayonara China
and I I flew home from San Francisco and
I went to my doctor because none of your
business but I was in the waiting room
and the doctor's office and I was
reading this little pam-4 was a tiny
little Pam feels like a pamphlet and
the pamphlet said that one out of every
three Americans is morbidly obese so
once again look we are sitting if the
person sitting on your left and the
person sitting on your right is the same
person you're probably not morbidly
obese but you might want to step out of
their feed zone for a minute it's not
that we're getting more obese people
just that non obese people are
disappearing and snack related incidents
at an alarming rate
[Music]
I live now I moved from Arizona I live
in in Washington DC you might not know
this people around the country pay taxes
so that people around Washington DC can
attend world-class museums and other
cultural venues free of charge so thanks
for that that's great I went to the
National Zoo hoping to see some national
animals you know like pigeon or sewer
rat but everybody there is lined up to
see what Panda yeah which is not a
national animal it's an immigrant and
it's stealing jobs from American animals
[Music]
[Applause]
what's black and white and red all over
communists panda from China they just
they deported one a couple of weeks ago
I don't know if you remember he lost his
green card or thought it was a bamboo
leaf and ate it and then they sent him
home bye-bye Bao Bao there's one
American bison at the National Zoo and a
whole herd of foreign-born elephants you
know why they're cheaper they pay them
peanuts listen maybe I'm old-fashioned
but I think the National Zoo should be
kept here with national animals and then
we can build a separate yet equally in
turn a tional zoo for all of those guys
right Canadian geese and German Shepherd
Spanish Fly polar bears are extinct ting
did you know that they're sinking why
are you telling me I just told you
they're extinct ting glaciers are
melting and that's just the tip of an
iceberg something like that the science
guy was talking very fast they're dying
announced a group and the government is
wants to save them and I'm a little
skeptical because for years black bears
and bears of color have been hunted and
killed for years
no-one's done a thing about it but the
second that the polar bear is barely
threatened the White House drops
everything
there are physiological differences
between the bear races everybody knows
that polar bears evolved in the Arctic
and there are no trees in the Arctic so
they never learn how to climb trees so
as they evolved they're missing certain
muscle groups in the back which is why
white bears can't jump
[Applause]
sure they're great swimmers I have a
theory
I have a theory about people who work at
the zoo I think they start in Capitol
Hill and then they lose their job or
their boss gets voted out of office and
they take those job skills and they use
them at the zoo there was an older
attractive woman probably a lobbyist in
her day now she's at the big cat exhibit
spinning lies about big cats come on
down check out the cheetah - world's
fastest land mammal it can run 70 miles
an hour 70 miles in one hour you can't
even do that in a car so I said I'm
gonna watch this I watched that cheetah
for an hour guess how many miles it went
none it lifted up its head and went back
to sleep so whatever that is one five
thousandth of a mile and so I corner her
and that's when the lies in the spin
come out oh it can't run a whole hour at
a time it can only run a few minutes at
a time and then if it catches what it's
chasing it's gonna stop running right
then and then it'll eat it and I don't
know how much of it it eats and I don't
know how big it was or little it was but
it turns out I know in a week a cheetah
might run five miles in a week well I
were on 15 miles in a week so if you use
the Pythagorean theorem which is rate
times time equals distance
turns out I'm three times faster than
the world's fastest land mammal so
[Music]
so please quit lying about the cheetah
cougar I travel all over and people want
to know
Robert Mac and as a get famous or they
want to know more Robert Mack so I
started a fan club it's called no more
Robert Mac and it's really catching on
once people realize Who I am they start
chanting it's so loudly
no more robber back no more robber mac
that I can't even finish but I do I do
have a lot of fans all over and they
seem to have a short attention span so I
brought some jokes for them and we'll
we'll finish with some of these jokes so
give me 60 seconds on the clock and go
how many landlords does it take to screw
in a light bulb
none also she won't fix the sink next
time you get some round-trip airline
tickets and they ask what your final
destination is say here it's a
round-trip I don't have time to explain
each of these to you guys
four times three is 12 yes never buy
sushi at the 99-cent store true story I
wish I was the guy who invented hot
cakes because you know how well those
things have sold like wildfire Pass if
Barack Obama's deceased mother married
the ghost of Osama bin Laden
she'd be mono bomb Osama
I went to a silent auction I got a dog
whistle and two mimes ice to be a
paperboy then I became a real boy this
one's really good or really bad
depending on whether you get it or not
so it's all on your shoulders so listen
up extra clothes I went shopping at a
cherry stand and a microphone store
bought a bing bada boom sold my chest at
a pawn shop son of a bishop rook me I'm
trying to meet new people I belong to a
gym he's very possessive I call this one
ice-cream cone cone
[Laughter]
once when I was littler we got a dog and
a cat the next day we named the dog
curiosity didn't have to name the can do
you like cats nothing like the musical I
went to a dyslexic masseuse really rub
me the wrong way and finally I went to
the bank the other day and said to the
teller I need $50 the teller said
withdrawal so i said i'm v of dollars
that's it for me i'm robber mac
[Applause]